Continuing Studies fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Credit Programs, 1974 - 1998; F-94-3; 2.37 m of textual records
  - Prison Education Program, 1980 - 1993; F-94-3-6; 94 cm of textual records
    - Administration, 1980 - 1993; F-94-3-6-1; 29 cm of textual records
      - Prison Education Program budget, 1992 - 1993; F-94-3-6-1-32 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
        Reviewed for access (Nov 24, 2023) – The bulk of the file is open. However, it includes a small number of documents (2) that contain the personal information of identifiable individuals (employment history). Restricted documents have been removed (enclosed); the rest of the file is open. Enclosed records may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
    - Contracts, 1985 - 1992; F-94-3-6-2; 20 cm of textual records
      - Regional Library proposals, 1985; F-94-3-6-2-1 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - SFU Prison Education Program contract, 1985 - 1986; F-94-3-6-2-2 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
        Open, no restrictions
        Reviewed for access (Nov 24, 2023) – File is open, no restricted information identified.
      - SFU Prison Education Program contract, 1986 - 1987; F-94-3-6-2-3 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - SFU Prison Education Program contract - correspondence, 1986 - 1987; F-94-3-6-2-4 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
        Restricted
        Reviewed for access (Nov 24, 2023) – File includes records that contain the personal information of identifiable individuals (employment history). File restricted in whole, but may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
      - Library contract, 1986 - 1987; F-94-3-6-2-5 (Archival box - standard 94-26)
        Open, reading room
        Reviewed for access (Nov 21, 2023) – File includes records that contain some individuals' personal contact information. File can be accessed in the Archives' reading room, but will be redacted in any digital access copies made by Archives.
      - Library contract - correspondence, 1986 - 1987; F-94-3-6-2-6 (Archival box - standard 94-26)
        Reviewed for access (Nov 23, 2023) – File includes records that contain the personal information of identifiable indviduals (social insurance number, personal contact information, educational history, employment history). File restricted in whole, but may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
      - SFU Prison Education Program contract, 1987 - 1988; F-94-3-6-2-7 (Archival box - standard 94-26)
        Reviewed for access (Nov 23, 2023) – File is open, no restricted information identified.
      - SFU Prison Education Program contract - correspondence, 1987 - 1988; F-94-3-6-2-8 (Archival box - standard 94-26)
      - SFU Prison Education Program contract - correspondence, 1987 - 1990; F-94-3-6-2-9 (Archival box - standard 94-26)
        Reviewed for access (Nov 23, 2023) – The bulk of the file is open. However, it includes a small number of documents (3) that contain the personal information of identifiable individuals (employment history). Restricted documents have been removed (enclosed); the rest of the file is open. Enclosed records may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
      - Library contract - correspondence, 1987 - 1988; F-94-3-6-2-10 (Archival box - standard 94-26)
      - Library contract, 1987 - 1988; F-94-3-6-2-11 (Archival box - standard 94-26)
      - SFU Prison Education Program contract - correspondence, 1988 - 1989; F-94-3-6-2-12 (Archival box - standard 94-26)
        Reviewed for access (Nov 23, 2023) – The bulk of the file is open. However, it includes a small number of documents (1) that contain the personal information of identifiable individuals (educational history, criminal history). Restricted documents have been removed (enclosed); the rest of the file is open. Enclosed records may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
      - SFU Prison Education Program contract, 1988 - 1989; F-94-3-6-2-13 (Archival box - standard 94-26)
      - Library contract, 1988 - 1989; F-94-3-6-2-14 (Archival box - standard 94-26)
        Reviewed for access (Nov 23, 2023) – The bulk of the file is open. However, it includes a small number of documents (1) that contain the personal information of identifiable individuals (employment history). Restricted documents have been removed (enclosed); the rest of the file is open. Enclosed records may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
      - Library contract - correspondence, 1988 - 1989; F-94-3-6-2-15 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
        Access review (Nov 16, 2023) – File is open, no restricted information identified.
      - Library contract - correspondence, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-6-2-16 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
      - SFU Prison Education Program contract - correspondence, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-6-2-17 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
        Access review (Nov 17, 2023) – File is open, no restricted information identified.
      - SFU Prison Education Program contract, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-6-2-18 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
        Reviewed for access (Nov 20, 2023) – File is open, no restricted information identified.
      - Library contract, 1989 - 1991; F-94-3-6-2-19 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
        Reviewed for access (Nov 20, 2023) – The bulk of the file is open. However, it includes a small number of documents (3) that contain the personal information of identifiable individuals (educational history, employment history, third party opinions about individual). Restricted documents have been removed (enclosed); the rest of the file is open. Enclosed records may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
      - SFU Prison Education Program contract, 1990 - 1991; F-94-3-6-2-20 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
        Reviewed for access (Nov 17, 2023): no restrictions identified.
      - Library contract - not accepted, 1991; F-94-3-6-2-21 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
      - Library contracts, 1991 - 1992; F-94-3-6-2-22 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
        Reviewed for access (Nov 20, 2023) – The bulk of the file is open. However, it includes a small number of documents (1) that contain the personal information of identifiable individuals (employment history). Restricted documents have been removed (enclosed); the rest of the file is open. Enclosed records may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
    - Courses, 1984 - 1993; F-94-3-6-3; 16 cm of textual records
      - Course scheduling, 1984 - 1985; F-94-3-6-3-1 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
        Access review (Nov 14, 2023) – File is open, no restricted information identified.
      - Ferndale - course outlines, 1989; F-94-3-6-3-2 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
        Access review (Nov 14, 2023) – The bulk of the file is open. However, it includes a small number of documents (1) that contain the personal information of identifiable individuals (educational history). Restricted documents have been removed (enclosed); the rest of the file is open. Enclosed records may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
      - Kent - "K" unit courses, 1989; F-94-3-6-3-3 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
      - Metchosin - course outlines, 1989; F-94-3-6-3-4 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
        Access review (Nov 15, 2023) – File is open, no restricted information identified.
      - Course proposals - 1989, F-94-3-6-3-5 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
        Access review (Nov 15, 2023) – File includes records that contain the personal information of identifiable indviduals (personal contact information, educational history, financial history). File restricted in whole, but may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
      - Course proposals - 1990, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-6-3-6 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
        Access review (Nov 15, 2023) – File includes records that contain the personal information of identifiable individuals (financial history). File restricted in whole, but may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
      - Metchosin - course outlines, 1990; F-94-3-6-3-7 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
      - Mountain - course outlines, 1990; F-94-3-6-3-8 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
      - Matsqui - course outlines, 1990; F-94-3-6-3-9 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
      - Kent - course outlines, 1990; F-94-3-6-3-10 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
      - Matsqui - GED correspondence, 1990 - 1991; F-94-3-6-3-11 (Archival box - standard 94-27)
        Access review (Nov 15, 2023) – File includes records that contain the personal information of identifiable individuals (educational history). File restricted in whole, but may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
      - Course proposals - 1991, vol. 1, 1990 - 1991; F-94-3-6-3-12 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
        Access review (Nov 15, 2023) – File includes records that contain the personal information of identifiable individuals (personal contact information, social insurance number, educational history). File restricted in whole, but may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
      - Course proposals - 1991, vol. 2, 1990 - 1991; F-94-3-6-3-13 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
        Access review (Nov 15, 2023) – File includes records that contain the personal information of identifiable individuals (personal contact information, social insurance number, educational history, employment history). File restricted in whole, but may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
      - PEP - Directed Independent Study Courses, 1991 - 1992; F-94-3-6-3-14 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
        Access review (Nov 15, 2023) – The bulk of the file is open. However, it includes a small number of documents (1) that contain the personal information of identifiable individuals (educational history). Restricted documents have been removed (enclosed); the rest of the file is open. Enclosed records may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
      - Course proposals - 1992, 1991 - 1992; F-94-3-6-3-15 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
      - Course proposals - 1993, 1992; F-94-3-6-3-16 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
        Access review (Nov 15, 2023) – File includes records that contain the personal information of identifiable individuals (personal contact information, social insurance number, employment history, educational history). File restricted in whole, but may be accessed under a Research Agreement; consult the reference archivist for more information.
      - GED Mountain - enrolment, results, stats, 1992; F-94-3-6-3-17 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
      - William Head - course outlines, 1992; F-94-3-6-3-18 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
      - Metchosin - course outlines, 1992; F-94-3-6-3-19 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
      - Mountain - course outlines, 1992; F-94-3-6-3-20 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
      - Matsqui - course outlines, 1992; F-94-3-6-3-21 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
      - Metchosin - course outlines, 1993; F-94-3-6-3-22 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
      - Mountain - course outlines, 1993; F-94-3-6-3-23 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
      - Matsqui - course outlines, 1993; F-94-3-6-3-24 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
    - Institutional Library program, 1986 - 1992; F-94-3-6-4; 28 cm of textual records
      - Kent - library correspondence, 1986 - 1987; F-94-3-6-4-1 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
      - Mountain - library correspondence, 1986 - 1988; F-94-3-6-4-2 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
      - Kent - library correspondence, 1987; F-94-3-6-4-3 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
      - Library Technicians meetings, 1987 - 1988; F-94-3-6-4-4 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
      - Mission - library correspondence, 1987 - 1988; F-94-3-6-4-5 (Archival box - standard 94-28)
      - William Head - library correspondence, vol. 1, 1987 - 1989; F-94-3-6-4-6 (Archival box - standard 94-29)
      - William Head - library correspondence, vol. 2, 1987 - 1989; F-94-3-6-4-7 (Archival box - standard 94-29)
      - Library - administrative correspondence, 1987 - 1992; F-94-3-6-4-8 (Archival box - standard 94-29)
      - Library Technicians meetings, 1988 - 1989; F-94-3-6-4-9 (Archival box - standard 94-29)
      - Mountain - library correspondence, 1988 - 1990; F-94-3-6-4-10 (Archival box - standard 94-29)
      - Kent - library correspondence, 1989; F-94-3-6-4-11 (Archival box - standard 94-29)
      - Library correspondence, 1989; F-94-3-6-4-12 (Archival box - standard 94-29)
      - Library Technicians meetings, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-6-4-13 (Archival box - standard 94-29)
      - Mission - library correspondence, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-6-4-14 (Archival box - standard 94-29)
      - William Head - library correspondence, 1989 - 1991; F-94-3-6-4-15 (Archival box - standard 94-29)
      - Kent - library correspondence, 1990 - 1991; F-94-3-6-4-16 (Archival box - standard 94-29)
      - Library Technicians meetings, 1990 - 1991; F-94-3-6-4-17 (Archival box - standard 94-29)
      - Mission - library correspondence, 1990 - 1992; F-94-3-6-4-18 (Archival box - standard 94-30)
      - Mountain - library correspondence, 1990 - 1992; F-94-3-6-4-19 (Archival box - standard 94-30)
      - Library Technicians meetings, 1991 - 1992; F-94-3-6-4-20 (Archival box - standard 94-30)
      - Kent - library correspondence, 1991 - 1992; F-94-3-6-4-21 (Archival box - standard 94-30)
      - Metchosin - library correspondence, 1991 - 1992; F-94-3-6-4-22 (Archival box - standard 94-30)
      - Regional Psychiatric Centre - library correspondence, 1991 - 1992; F-94-3-6-4-23 (Archival box - standard 94-30)
  - SFU/Secwepemc Cultural Education Society (SCES) Program, 1988 - 1998; F-94-3-7; 12 cm of textual records; Secwepemc Cultural Education Society
    The SFU/Secwepemc Cultural Education Society university program began in 1988 as a one-year pilot project with nineteen aboriginal students taking introductory courses in sociology and anthropology. In 1989 the University and the Shuswap Nation entered a formal three-year agreement, followed by another long-term agreement in 1992 to cooperatively run the program which focuses on making university education accessible to aboriginal students. Located on the Kamloops Indian Reserve, the curriculum offers an integrated university program with an emphasis on First Nations studies, research and social sciences. Students can earn credits towards diplomas, certificates, minors or majors in First Nations Studies, Anthropology, Sociology, or Archaeology. It is the first post-secondary institute in British Columbia that offers university level courses in aboriginal languages such as Secwepemc (Shuswap), Upper and Lower Statimc (Lillooet), and Nle7kepmx (Thompson). In 1991 an Archaeology Field School was established and is the only university program for First Nations of its kind in Canada that allows students to receive hands-on experience in archaeological site identification, survey techniques, site testing, excavation and cultural resource management. Campus facilities in Kamloops include administrative and faculty offices, class and seminar rooms, a computer lab, student lounge, resource library, reading room and a dedicated archaeology laboratory.
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the administration of the SFU/Secwepemc Cultural Education Society Program. Activities, events and topics documented include program development, the SFU/SCES Joint Committee, and planning for the 10-year program anniversary in 1998. Records include correspondence, minutes, working papers, contracts, course outlines, budget and financial working papers, questionnaires, and publications.
    Secwepemc Cultural Education Society
    - SFU/SCES contract, 1988; F-94-3-7-0-1 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Budget, 1988 - 1989; F-94-3-7-0-2 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Program planning and meetings, 1988 - 1989; F-94-3-7-0-3 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Correspondence, 1988 - 1989; F-94-3-7-0-4 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Course outlines, 1988; F-94-3-7-0-5 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Course and instruction planning, 1988; F-94-3-7-0-6 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Course outlines, 1989; F-94-3-7-0-7 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Course instruction and planning, 1989; F-94-3-7-0-8 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - SFU/SCES contract, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-7-0-9 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Budget, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-7-0-10 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Program planning and SFU/SCES Joint Committee, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-7-0-11 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Correspondence, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-7-0-12 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Program planning and SFU/SCES Joint Committee, 1990; F-94-3-7-0-13 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Course and instruction planning, 1990; F-94-3-7-0-14 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Course outlines, 1990; F-94-3-7-0-15 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Student questionnaire, 1990; F-94-3-7-0-16 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Correspondence, 1990 - 1991; F-94-3-7-0-17 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - SFU/SCES contract, vol. 1, 1990 - 1992; F-94-3-7-0-18 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - SFU/SCES contract, vol. 2, 1990 - 1992; F-94-3-7-0-19 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Course outlines, 1991; F-94-3-7-0-20 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - SFU/SCES contract amendments, 1991; F-94-3-7-0-21 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Course and instruction planning, 1991; F-94-3-7-0-22 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - Budget amendments, 1991 - 1992; F-94-3-7-0-23 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
    - 10 Year Anniversary Celebration, 1998; F-94-3-7-0-24 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
  - Health and Fitness Studies Certificate Program, 1978 - 1991; F-94-3-8; 1 cm of textual records
    The Certificate Program in Health and Fitness Studies was established in 1978 drawing largely upon the resources of the Department of Kinesiology. Developed for sport coaches, those supervising training and/or fitness programs, and the general public, the program provides an opportunity to complete a coordinated program of university study on a full or part time basis in the areas of health, fitness, and nutrition. In the program's early years, students could earn a certificate by completing a series of credit courses from Kinesiology, Chemistry, Psychology, and Fine and Performing Arts along with a series of scheduled non-credit activities organized to allow students to meet with faculty and professionals in the field. Credit from these courses could also be used towards a Bachelor's degree. The program has evolved with an emphasis on Kinesiology courses and as of 2005, continues to be offered as an undergraduate certificate by the School of Kinesiology in the Faculty of Applied Sciences.
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the administration of the Health and Fitness Studies Certificate program. Activities, events and topics documented include program and course development, correspondence with students, enrollment statistics, and program guidelines. Records include correspondence, working papers, program brochures, and statistics.
    - Correspondence and working papers, 1978 - 1991; F-94-3-8-0-1 (Archival box - standard 94-31)
- Non-credit programs, 1986 - 1999; F-94-4; 94 cm of textual records 11 photographs 2 contact sheets; Physical description: 11 photographs located in F-94-4-3-1-9
  Series consists of records relating to the administration and development of non-credit courses and programs offered by the Office of Continuing Studies and sponsored by SFU's academic faculties, departments and schools. Records include correspondence; working papers; reports; budgets and financial working papers; course proposals, outlines and evaluations; agendas and minutes; program contracts; student binders; pamphlets; and photographs and contact sheets.
  - Applied Sciences Continuing Education Program, 1989 - 1999; F-94-4-1; 34 cm of textual records
    The Applied Science Continuing Education program has offered a series of non-credit certificate programs in the areas of Communication, Computing Science, Engineering, Kinesiology and Resource and Environmental Management since 1989. Courses, seminars, workshops, and conferences are developed as a result of faculty support and industry demand with changing technological needs often dictating course content. In the 1990s an autonomous Faculty of Applied Sciences Continuing Education Unit was created that reported directly to the Dean of the Faculty of Applied Sciences. However, the unit proved to be financially unsustainable so in 2002 it was downsized and its administrative control was returned to the Dean of Continuing Studies.
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the development and administration of the Applied Sciences Continuing Education program. Activities, events and topics documented include general programs offered in the Applied Science Continuing Education Program (including specifically designed in-house programs), computer programming and Internet courses; international programs on management techniques and cultural orientation; project management; and risk assessment and decision analysis for management of natural resources. Also documented are external programs sponsored by Applied Science Continuing Education such as The Institute for Government Informatics Professionals and The Technology Industries Association (TIA) Business Program. Records include correspondence, working papers, minutes, course outlines, program evaluations, contracts, and pamphlets.
    - General programs, 1989 - 1998; F-94-4-1-1; 5 cm of textual records
      - Digital Cellular and Personal Telecommunications: Network Concepts and Technologies, 1989 - 1990; F-94-4-1-1-1 (Archival box - standard 94-32)
      - Business and Management: The World Economy After 1992, 1990; F-94-4-1-1-2 (Archival box - standard 94-32)
      - Legal Information Systems, 1993; F-94-4-1-1-3 (Archival box - standard 94-32)
      - TURBO-CNE, 1993; F-94-4-1-1-4 (Archival box - standard 94-32)
      - Environmental Impact Assessment - Toosey Indian Band, 1993; F-94-4-1-1-5 (Archival box - standard 94-32)
      - High Technology Industry Course Assessment, 1994; F-94-4-1-1-6 (Archival box - standard 94-32)
      - Continuous Innovation in Advanced Technology, 1994 - 1995; F-94-4-1-1-7 (Archival box - standard 94-32)
      - Jeff Tash Seminar on Client Services, 1994 - 1995; F-94-4-1-1-8 (Archival box - standard 94-32)
      - Designing an Effective Survey, 1995; F-94-4-1-1-9 (Archival box - standard 94-32)
      - Out of the Box Thinking Workshop, 1995 - 1996; F-94-4-1-1-10 (Archival box - standard 94-32)
      - Personal Communication Systems (PCS), 1995 - 1996; F-94-4-1-1-11 (Archival box - standard 94-32)
      - Micro Hydroelectric Systems, 1995 - 1996; F-94-4-1-1-12 (Archival box - standard 94-32)
      - Virtual-U: Management Skills for ITAs, 1996; F-94-4-1-1-13 (Archival box - standard 94-32)
      - ITAO conference, 1996; F-94-4-1-1-14 (Archival box - standard 94-32)
      - Introduction to Digital Signal Processing Technology, 1998; F-94-4-1-1-15 (Archival box - standard 94-32)